m: 980.228.8926 marshman.cory@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Career-long record of operations, business development, and management innovation for leading businesses

Proven talent for aligning business strategy and operational objectives to achieve maximum operational performance and success with minimum resource expenditures. Growth-focused leader and exceptional administrator with keen interpersonal communication, and organizational skills, as well as budget management, marketing development, and resource allocation expertise.

Professional Experience

INNER PEAKS CLIMBING CENTER

FEBRUARY 2018 - PRESENT

DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS

- Manage 3 facilities totaling over 65,000 sqft. which services 1,800+ monthly members and 10,000+ monthly active users
- Recruit, hire, develop and mentor 60+ service-oriented, collaborative, passionate team members
- Manage 60+ staff as the head of 3 departments; Marketing, Product Development and Operations
- Orchestrated and managed a company-wide restructuring in collaboration of the Ownership group
- Execute integrated marketing program campaigns by leveraging diverse marketing assets including grassroots, print, digital and social media
- Oversee the company's global marketing structure
- Ensure a consistent social media presence that meets with our brand and appearance standards
- Direct operations and logistics of 25+ local and regional programs and events a year
- Manage and collaborate with the ownership group on a \$4-Million 18,0000 sqft. new facility, with a
 focus on strategic business growth, risk mitigation and facility operations development
- Build relationships across the local and national industry
- Handle all profit and loss tracking based on cost of staffing and cost per pass
- Audit and augment company training and on-boarding program to comply with OSHA requirements, insurance mandates and company policy
- Complete yearly insurance renewals for each facility and maintain compliance with insurance company and industry standards
- Review, log and follow up with all accident and incident reports, and train staff on EAP

US NATIONAL WHITEWATER CENTER

OCT 2015 - FEB 2018

PROGRAM MANAGER

- Developed and implement new programming to create cohesive policies and procedures while aligning efforts of multiple departments to implement programming
- Maintained a fleet of over 500+ bikes serving over 40 miles of trails and managed a team of 10+ bike mechanics, 5 bike program coordinators and 1000's of daily users
- Pioneered and operated the world's first deep-water-solo climbing program while managing the operational budget for the \$4-million facility
- Hired, trained and managed 200+ staff members, serving up to 15,000 guests per day
- Forecasted yearly budgets, maintained records of compliance and adherence, and analyzed daily cost per pass estimates to mitigate staffing costs
- Organized and hosted the pro-level Tuck Fest deep water solo climbing competition with a \$15,000 purse and sponsored professional level talent, in conjunction with 12 other outdoor industry events
- Orchestrated center-wide, cross-departmental dispatch operations, and staff and guest safety efforts

Cory Marshman Page 2

CARE FOR DOGS, THAILAND

Jun 2014 - DEC 2014

SHELTER MANAGER (Temporary Consultant)

- Directed day-to-day operational tasks including all staff and volunteers at the shelter
- Coordinated adoptions & outreach programs/events
- Maximized a limited annual budget of \$150,000 to vaccinate, feed, and house over 500 dogs
- Spearheaded a 'Trap, Neuter, Vaccinate & Release' program, sterilizing over 600 dogs
- Guided, trained, and mentored a local Thai shelter manager to take over upon the expiration of my work Visa

ALL HANDS, THE PHILIPPINES

Jan 2014 - May 2014

PROJECT MANAGER (Temporary Consultant)

- Researched and planned the rebuilding of 250 homes with a budget of \$500,000 & supervised a staff of over 60 people in partnership with Habitat for Humanity
- Recruited, inspired, and enabled a Filipino leadership team of 10 to take over after the planning phase
- Represented the organization to the local and international community & government leaders
- Composed and submitted weekly reports providing progress updates, activities, and expenses

USA, SOUTH KOREA, CHINA, MYANMAR, OMAN, DECEMBER 2008 - OCTOBER 2015

ESL INSTRUCTOR

- Taught general, conversational, and business English, locally & internationally to students ranging from kindergarten to adult
- Organized and hosted English seminars & events for thousands of students
- Engineered curriculum and new study material for all courses

INNER PEAKS CLIMBING CENTER

October 2004 - December 2008

Operations Manager

- Controlled operational tasks, 60+ staff, and client relations at the facility
- Customized, coordinated, and oversaw rock climbing fundraisers and events
- Fostered the development of youth programs and promotional marketing
- Managed staff training, onboarding and offboarding

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

BACHELOR OF ART (B.A.) IN ANTHROPOLOGY, 2008

University of North Carolina, Charlotte, NC

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

VOLUNTEERISM:

- All Hands Volunteers in the Philippines as a disaster relief volunteer & team leader, 2014
- F.R.E.S.H. Nepal, in Kathmandu Nepal as a live-in volunteer, 2012
- AmeriCorps in the USA as an assistant social worker & ESL teacher, 2007 2008
- Nature House Conservation Sea Turtle Rescue as a live-in volunteer, 2001
- Habitat for Humanity as a construction volunteer on various projects, 2002, 2007, 2008, 2010
- Boy Scouts of America Eagle Scout with 400+ hour service project 2002

Additional Information

Technical Proficiencies: Windows, Mac OS, Microsoft Office Suite, Microsoft Project, Excel VBA, Formsite, Max Panda, Mind Body, Adobe (Photoshop, InDesign and Lightroom), QuickBooks, Eventbrite, PayPal, MailChimp, Siriusware, When I Work and Humanity HRIS Platforms, Social Media Platforms, Office 360, SharePoint, Google Docs, DropBox, Hootsuite, HubSpot, Google and Facebook Analytics, Rock Gym Pro, ADP, Workday, Agile, Lean Six Sigma Training

Hobbies & Global Experience: Outdoor education, lived in and traveled to over 28 different countries, 2800-mile self-guided bike trip across China, Search and Rescue training, Ultra-running: completed 50k and 50-mile races, Self-guided expedition to Everest base camp, Black Diamond level skier